Guide to the New-York Historical Society Collection of New York City Miscellaneous Manuscripts, circa 1614-1933 (bulk 1641-1900) MS 443.19
New-York Historical Society
- Account of Mrs. Elizabeth Van Thright, signed by Henry Lane, merchant, 1729 July 11 (Box 2, Folder 28)
- Appraisement of goods and chattel of the late widow, Margaret Steward, 1729 May 19 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  Goods includes 2 aprons, a new calico gown, a bible
- Consideration by Committee held at Fort George of proposal of the Mayor of New York, 1730 August 7 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  Documents relates to John Montgomerie's grant of the amended charter of George II in 1730
- Receipt of Mr. John Jacob Vandeusen, signed John Groesbeck, Jr., 1728 August 27 (Box 2, Folder 36)
- Copy of Warrant relating to maintenance of militia, signed by Peter Winne, 1728 September 27 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  On bottom is a note that warrant was improperly drawn. On back is statement that men acting upon warrant distressed 11 pewter plates.
- Copy of Oath taken by the Freemen of New York City, undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Accounts of Evert Wendell & Daughter, 1729-1734 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Letter by John Groesbeck to Evert Evender (?), Attorney at Law, Albany, 1731 October (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Number of Souls in the Province of New York, as taken by Constables, 1731;1738 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  Includes number of souls on the Island of New York as taken by Constables in May 1731
- Letter [Dutch?] to DeCewarde Predirant (?) in Albany from B.E. Vrients (?), 1732 May 29 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Petition of Abraham Glen, Abraham Truax (?), Phillip Schuyler to purchase land from Native Indians, signed by William Cosby, 1733 November 3 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  Property in County of Albany
- Order to Gose (?) Van Schyeck to appear before judge and supreme court, 1733 August 9 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Sworn release. Lawrence Van DerSpiegel and Elsie Lodegare received thirty pounds from Elsie Sanders of Albany, deceased, 1734 June 29 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- The jurors present Mary Harvy of the North Ward of the city for assaulting and beating Elizabeth Richards on October 31st, undated (Box 3, Folder 2)
  Signed by Johannes Hardenbrook (representative) and witnessed by Elizabeth Richards
- Map or Survey of swamp in Montgomery Ward, signed by James Roosevelt, John Roosevelt, A.C. Van Wyck, John Chambers. 2 Copies., 1734 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Order of fabric and sewing supplies from Catharine Staats to Messrs. Storke and Gainsboro, London, 1735 December 12 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Account of James Delancey, Cadwalader Colden and Captain Nelson, 1735-1742 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Petition of Israel Horsfield, Timothy Horsfield and Richard Green, butchers of New York City, to Mayor and City Council, 1735 August (Box 3, Folder 7)
  Grievances
- Jury judgment in favor of William Jamison against Anna Ten Eyck for damages, 1735 July 15 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  Trespass charge against Anna Ten Eyck; two pounds for damages
- Jury judgment that Sheriff inquire concerning debt (19 pounds) of Anna Ten Eyck owed to Jeremiah Lattouck, 1735 July 15 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Jury judgment in favor of John Peers against Anna Ten Eyck for damages, 1735 July 15 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  Trespass charge and two pounds for damages
- Inquisition at house of Robert Todd situated at Broad Street, signed by Sheriff John Symes, 1735 July 14 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  Jeremiah Lattouck sustained damages of 11 pounds, signed by sheriff and 12 men of the jury
- Inquisition at house of Robert Todd situated at Broad Street, signed by Sheriff John Symes, 1735 July 14 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  John Peers sustained damages of two pounds, two shillings, signed by sheriff and 12 men of the jury
- Inquisition at house of Robert Todd situated at Broad Street, signed by Sheriff John Symes, 1735 July 14 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  William Jamison sustained damages of two pounds, six shillings, signed by sheriff and 12 men of the jury
- Page from Account Book listing Derrick Schuyler, Anna Vanderspeigel, John Pintard, Abraham Vanwyke, John Hamilton, 1736 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- 1737 Minutes of Meeting of Common Council, Taken by Will Sharpas, 1737 June 11 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  Minutes concern application of John Chambers to rebuild front of house to make more uniform along Broadway; neighbors consented
- Copy of Articles of Agreement between Henry Crugor, Henry Cuylor, Joseph Scot and Gorardus Duycking and Adam van Allen for laying a wharf in the city of New York, 1739 November 20 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Election of Alderman, Assistant, Assessors, Collector, Constables of Dock Ward, signed by Peter Jay, 1739 September 29 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Election of Alderman, Assistant, Assessors, Collector, Constables of South Ward, signed by John Moore, 1739 September 29 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Proceeding about the City Seal in Common Council of New York, 1739 November 29 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  Document is written mainly in short-hand
- Receipt of Evert Wendell, signed by John Nicoll for four pounds, 1740 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Receipt for Mr. David Van Horne (Tannely (?) V. Lewis), 1741 March 22 (Box 3, Folder 18)
- Copy of Notes regarding residents of Brookland believed to be written by John Chambers, undated (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Receipts for Nicholas Bayard, 1741 December 1 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Receipt signed by C. Parker, 1742 March 18 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- 1742-1744 Account of Mr. John Nicole (William Mountaine) (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Public auction for two lots on Maiden Lane at request of Samuel Bayard, 1742 July 5 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- 1746 Account (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Letters Patent to Daniel Horsmanden revoking his Commission as Recorder of the City of New York, 1747 October 8 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Receipt for Sam Van Horne (Thomas Marshall), 1747 November 29 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- 1748 Account of Mr. John Sayor (Charles Nichols), 1748 December 8 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Corrected draft of petition of Robert Livingston, Delaney and Anthony Rutgers granting of land which is underwater, 1749 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  Addressed to The Worshipful the Corporation of the City of New York in Common Council Convened; Land is in South Ward of City
- Return weight of 18 bags of Cornell, 1749 October 11 (Box 3, Folder 18)
- Receipt for Samuel Van Horne (Gerard G. Beekman), 1749 October 31 (Box 3, Folder 18)
- Inquisition at house of Malcolm McEwen, signed by Sheriff John Ayscough and 12 jurors, 1750 November 10 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  Damages of three pounds, thirteen shillings
- 1751 Order of Claper of Amsterdam Re: Dr. Arondeus & Dr. Van Linder [Dutch] (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Inquisition at house of Thomas Caudell, signed by Coronor Anthony Butgers and 12 jurors, 1753 June 19 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  Damages of Twenty-four pounds, fourteen shillings
- Petition of John Kennedy for relief addressed to Attorney General William Kempe, 1753 September 16 (Box 3, Folder 20)
- Inquisition at house of Malcolm McEwen, signed by Sheriff John Ayscough and 12 jurors, 1753 August 27 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  Damages of two pounds, thirteen shillings
- Proclamation of Council of New York (1813 copy), 1753 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  Robert Van Deusen and son apprehended and brought to jail
- Two receipts – 1 for John Sands; 1 for J. Van Benthuyne, both signed by John Jauncey, 1754 (Box 3, Folder 26)
- Receipt for thirty pounds delivered to Lydia Brasure living on Stone Street (William Wood), 1754 February 19 (Box 3, Folder 26)
- Inquisition at Royal Exchange, signed by Sheriff John Roberts and 12 jurors, 1754 July 15 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  Damages of ten pounds, eleven shillings
- Petition of Petitioner, formerly property of McWillet, merchant, and presently property of Captain Carney, for relief addressed to Attorney General William Kempe, undated (Box 3, Folder 22)
  Petitioner having been captured by the French in the Barbados and having escaped, pleads for his liberty.
- Affidavit of Daniel Stiles RE: Sloop Friendship, 1755 June 13 (Box 3, Folder 23)
- Receipt (Purchase of slave) for Daniel Flandreau (Charles Nichols), 1755 August 6 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  53 pounds, 6 shillings and 8 pence for Mrs. Catherine Barberie Momaryneck
- Receipt of Captain Truger (Jacob Van Wagner), 1755 November 19 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  29 bags of Cornell
- 1755 Report from City Council (1813 copy) (Box 3, Folder 28)
  Controversy between New York Province and Massachusetts Bay Province
- Receipt for Gerard G. Beekman (Charles Nichols), 1756 April 29 (Box 3, Folder 25)
- Receipt for John Sanders (Robert & Richard Ray), 1756 June 21 (Box 3, Folder 25)
- Receipt for John Hunter account (Fran Stephens), 1756 September 22 (Box 3, Folder 25)
- Receipt for Charles Nichols (Garret Van Horne), 1756 November 3 (Box 3, Folder 25)
- Bill of Exchange for 100 pounds (Lewis Pintard), 1756 December 12 (Box 3, Folder 25)
- Power of Attorney of John Gaa, signed by John Gaa & William Bard, 1757 February 23 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Order signed by Daniel Horsmanden, 1757 January 19 (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Inquisition at City Hall Re: Damages of 130 pounds, signed by Sheriff John Roberts and 12 jurors, 1757 May 2 (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Receipt for Mr. Humphrey Jones (Isaac Roosevelt), 1757 July 6 (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Bill of Exchange for 150 pounds paid unto Delancey Robinson & Company, 1757 May 25 (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Receipt for Charles Nichols (William Kelly), 1757 June 18 (Box 3, Folder 17)
- John Beekman Account (Josiah Ogden), 1757 September 3 (Box 3, Folder 26)
- Order sent to Honorable James Delancey, Lt. Governor forbidding Tunis Rivelt from piloting vessels, 1757 December 5 (Box 3, Folder 18)
- Testimonial to William Coventry, Alderman of the Dock, Ward of the City, Justice of the Peace, 1758 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  Signed by numerous New Yorkers, including Van Wyck, Beekman, Schuyler
- Receipt of William DePeyster, bought chocolate, 1758 (Box 3, Folder 36)
- Account of Charles Nichols, Bought cask of coffee from Ship St. Fernando, 1758 September 6 (Box 3, Folder 36)
- Receipt for Cask Indigo bought out of the prize ship Juno (Charles Nichols), 1759 April 30 (Box 3, Folder 43)
- Deposition of Ann Devimes (?), sister of Elizabeth Wraxall, searched for papers of Peter Wraxall, deceased, for Will, 1759 July (Box 3, Folder 41)
- Bill of Exchange for Mr. Lewis Pintard for 75 pounds (Henry Uhthoff, Esq., London), 1759 December 15 (Box 3, Folder 43)
- Receipt for rent of 25 pounds by Mrs. Penellope Nicholas (Sarah Von Solingen), 1759 May 1 (Box 3, Folder 43)
- Bill of Exchange for Mr. Lewis Pintard for 75 pounds (Henry Uhthoff, Esq., London), 1759 December 15 (Box 3, Folder 43)
- Receipt book and Bills of Exchanges (Edward and Charles Nichols, William Waddell), 1759 (Box 3, Folder 44)
- Citation on Complaint of one Executor that the other refuses to prove or deliver the Will of Elbert Gerritse, by James Delancey, Lt. Governor, 1759 (Box 3, Folder 45)
- Order sent to Abraham Wendell to pay Manuel Josephson 62 pounds, 1760 April 28 (Box 3, Folder 18)
- Account of Captain Banks (Catherine Heysham), 1760 June, July, August (Box 3, Folder 31)
  Items include check fabric, buttons, handkerchiefs, shoes
- Bill of April 25, 1760 (Richard Hunter), 1760 April 25 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  Mr. Walsh bought twelve casks of butter from Richard Hunter
- Bread Bill of May 4, 1760 (Evert Byvanch), 1760 May 4 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  Mr. Frances Welch bought bread from Evert Byvanch
- Bill of July 2, 1760 (Henry Van Vleck), 1760 July 2 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  Mr. John Empich bought men's clothing items, primarily, from Henry Van Vleck
- Receipt of Joseas Smith, 1760 (Box 3, Folder 32)
- Affidavit by Daniel Bloom, undated (Box 3, Folder 32)
  Daniel Bloom in danger and fears bodily harm from Richard Marsh and John Cushins
- March Account of Frances Welsh (Jon Fish), 1760 (Box 3, Folder 32)
- May Bread Account of Frances Welsh (Petrus Byvanch), 1760 May 4 (Box 3, Folder 32)
- April Account of Robert Alexander (Charles Nichols), 1760 April (Box 3, Folder 32)
- May Account of Frances Welsh (Caleb Lawrence), 1760 May (Box 3, Folder 32)
- Bill for repairing compass of schooner dolphin, Denis Candy, Master of schooner (Anthony Lamb), 1760 October (Box 3, Folder 32)
- Account of Nicholas Low (Charles Nichols), 1760 (Box 3, Folder 32)
- Account of George Foliot (Charles Nichols), 1760 January (Box 3, Folder 32)
  Bought cask of Flemish wine
- Account of John Empich (Thomas and James Franklin), 1760 July 2 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  Bought rum
- January Account of Jacob Remsen (Charles Nichols), 1760 January 2 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  Bought two barrels of beef
- Affidavit of Dirk Bradt Van Schoonhover attesting that he delivered and read declaration and letter to Johannes Muller, tenant, 1761 September 28 (Box 3, Folder 39)
- Current prices of goods imported from Amsterdam (Daniel Crommelin), 1761 May 8 (Box 3, Folder 39)
- Receipt for Privateer Iron Boscowan for Captain John Taylor (John Hertely), 1761 July 3 (Box 3, Folder 39)
- Citation to Catherine Rypele to Inventory John Rypele's Estate by Robert Moncklon, Governor Province of New York, 1761 (Box 3, Folder 40)
- Draft of Certificate of Proof of Peter Wraxall's Will by Cadwallader Colden, 1761 (Box 3, Folder 42)
- Release to Faulconier Valleau signed by John Bard, 1761 (Box 3, Folder 57)
- Receipt for goods to John Balthas Dasch (John G. Lansing), 1762 May 3 (Box 3, Folder 33)
- Receipt of inward tax due on Sloop Princess of Mecklinburgh (John Swift), 1762 September (Box 3, Folder 33)
  On back lists cargo on the Sloop Princess
- Account of Mr. Matthews (John V. Cortlandt), 1762 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  Bought cask of strained sugar
- Account of Daniel Mesnard (Charles Nichols), 1762 October (Box 3, Folder 33)
  Bought buttons, mohair, thread, et. al.
- Receipt of John Ellis (John Lansing, The Corporation of the City of New York), 1762 May 10 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  Ordered twenty lamps painted and glazed
- Receipt of Stephen Terhune (John Lansing, The Corporation of the City of New York), 1762 March 10 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  Ordered 45 lamps, glazed and painted, 10 panes
- Receipt of Robert Andrews (John Lansing, the Corporation of the City of New York), 1762 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  Ordered lamp irons, nails, new ring
- Receipt for Abraham Lazudas/Judah Hayes (Murray & Pearsalls), 1762 October 19 (Box 3, Folder 18)
- Receipt for Charles Nichols (James Rud), 1763 February 20 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  42 pounds for use of Crew of Iron Boscawen Sloop Two Friends
- Bill of Exchange for 100 pounds (Achson Thompson), 1763 June 11 (Box 3, Folder 34)
- Receipt of John Nicol (Jacob Ogden, loan officer Queen's County), 1763 April 19 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  30 pounds received of John Nicols
- List of Justices of the Peace in several counties within Province of New York, 1763 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  Albany County, Duchess County, Ulster County, Orange County, West Chester County, Suffolk County, Queens County, Kings County, Richmond County
- Whitehead Hicks admitted to be freeman and citizen of New York, signed by John Cruger, Mayor of New York, 1763 September 26 (Box 3, Folder 34)
- Bill of Samuel Preston (Theodore Van Wyck & Andrew Hamersly), 1763 December 15 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  Items include cloth, iron, nails, lace
- Receipt of Samuel Van Horne (James Abeel, Thomas Pettit), 1764 June (Box 3, Folder 37)
- Recognizance of debtors James Davis, John Young and ____ Bartlett, signed John Cruger, 1764 April 4 (Box 3, Folder 37)
- Receipt of Philip Lansing (Henry Will), 1764 May 16 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  Bought 1 gross of round spoons and 3 large chamber pots
- Weight of 48 barrels of Flour sold by Nicholas Governeur, 1764 April 7 (Box 3, Folder 37)
- Inventory of goods and chattel seized from Abraham Slot to pay quarter rent to Thomas Dewit, 1764 August 17 (Box 3, Folder 37)
- Receipt of Edward Laight (Charles Nichols), 1764 September (Box 3, Folder 37)
  Bought 4 hinges, 1 lock, 4 pounds nails
- Bill of Exchange for 40 pounds, Garret Rapalie (Messrs. Grubb & Wattson, Merchants of London), 1764 July 13 (Box 3, Folder 37)
- Invoice of James Nixon at the corner of Stone and Broad Streets (Robert Saundres), 1764 July 14 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  Includes buttons and mohair
- Account of Captain James Creighton (Charles Nichols), 1764 (Box 3, Folder 37)
- Appointment of Peter M. Waller as Administrator of Daniel Dowdell's Will, in place of John Waller, deceased, by Cadwallader Colden, Lt. Governor, 1764 (Box 3, Folder 38)
- Order to pay Charles Nichols 44 pounds, accepted by John Lamb, 1765 August 21 (Box 3, Folder 18)
- Account of Daniel Mesnard (Charles Nichols), 1765 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  Items include buttons, mohair, thread
- Master and Warden's Certificate in favor of branch pilots superseded for refusing their duty, undated (Box 3, Folder 37)
- Certificate of Gerard DePeyster as Freeman and Citizen of the City of New York, by John Cruger, Mayor of New York, 1765 October 1 (Box 3, Folder 46)
- Account of Corn Exported from New York in America between April 5, 1765 and April 5, 1766, 1765-1766 (Box 3, Folder 48)
- Affidavit re John Keating, signed by James Magra, Physician, 1765 July 29 (Box 3, Folder 49)
  John Keating would cause bodily harm
- Account of James Kerr (Smith Ramadge), 1765 November 1 (Box 3, Folder 50)
  Bought Jamaican Spirits
- Account of Francis Silvester (Charles Nichols), 1765 June 21 (Box 3, Folder 50)
- Receipt for Alexander Stewart, Charles Nichols, John Lamb (Sampson Simson), 1765 April 23 (Box 3, Folder 50)
  Bought a cargo of Port Wine imported on Brig Zane
- Receipt for rum for Charles Nichols (Thomas Pearsall), 1765 July 31 (Box 3, Folder 50)
- Weight of 55 barrels of flour sold to Lunio King (Volkert Dow), 1765 November 5 (Box 3, Folder 50)
- Account of Moore & Lynson (Charles Nichols), 1765 July 4 (Box 3, Folder 50)
- Bill of Exchange for Evert Bancher (Messrs. Richard Neave & Sons, Merchants in London), 1765 October 11 (Box 3, Folder 50)
- John Moore's Account of Quit Rents from September 29, 1765 to September 29, 1769, 1765-1769 (Box 3, Folder 51)
- Receipt for port wine for Joseph Allicock (Charles Nichols), 1765 May 31 (Box 3, Folder 52)
- Receipt for John Inness (Charels Nichols), 1765 November (Box 3, Folder 52)
  1 Quarter rent for cellar
- Receipt for Charles Nichols (John Goodridge), 1765 August 9 (Box 3, Folder 52)
  Three pounds, 16 shillings disbursed on nephew's account
- Receipt for sugar for Charles Nichols (John Jauncey), 1765 September 23 (Box 3, Folder 52)
- Copy of Minutes of a council held at Fort George certified by George Banyard, undated (Box 3, Folder 47)
  Issue of whether John Coe, John Parsells, and John VanderNoort should be removed as Justices of the Peace for exercising jurisdiction in a cause in which they were interested.
- Order for John Amiel's subsistence money, 1766 June 25 (Box 3, Folder 52)
- Order to Elisham Smith (Daniel Lake), 1766 October 16 (Box 3, Folder 52)
  Deliver effects to Evert Bancher, Jr.
- Receipt for sugar loaves for Charles Nichols (A. Cuylar), 1766 April 24 (Box 3, Folder 52)
- 1766 Account of Alexander Stewart (Charles Nichols) (Box 3, Folder 52)
- Receipt for sugar loaves for Charles Nichols (A. Cuylar), 1766 April 24; 1766 July 24 (Box 3, Folder 52)
- 1766 Account of Daniel Mesnard (Charles Nichols), 1766 May 14 (Box 3, Folder 52)
- Receipt for butter & bread for Jacobus Bogert (Charles Nichols), 1766 January 28 (Box 3, Folder 52)
- 1766 Account of Daniel Mesnard (Charels Nichols), 1766 December 24 (Box 3, Folder 52)
- Receipt for Jamaican spirits for Charles Nichols (William Denning), 1766 May 12 (Box 3, Folder 52)
- Receipt for sugar loaves for Charles Nichols (A. Cuylar), 1766 July 24 (Box 3, Folder 52)
- Receipt for box of tea for Mr. Nick Low (J.D. Peyster), 1766 January 15 (Box 3, Folder 52)
- Receipt for for rum for Charles Nichols (Sam Gifford), 1766 May 10 (Box 3, Folder 52)
- John Ihleen's Receipt for barrels of milk bread and whittles bread, 1766 April 10 (Box 3, Folder 52)
- Receipt for John Allicock (Charles Nichols), 1766 April 25 (Box 3, Folder 52)
- 1766 Account of Alexander Stewart (Charles Nichols), 1766 February 14 (Box 3, Folder 52)
- Receipt for Lewis Pintard (J. Noble), 1766 August 14 (Box 3, Folder 52)
- Receipt for Jas. Creighton for weight of barrels of flour (Hermanus Wendell), 1766 September 12 (Box 3, Folder 52)
- 1766 Certificate of Naval Officers of New York RE: Brigantine Pompey, 1766 June 27 (Box 3, Folder 53)
- 1766 Letter from and signed by Sons of Liberty RE: Stamp Act, 1766 February 14 (Box 3, Folder 54)
- Account Ledger/Minutes of Literary Society of New York, 1766-1772 (Box 3, Folder 56)
- Receipt of David Hayes (John Cruger, Mayor of New York), 1767 June (Box 3, Folder 34)
- Power of Attorney to John Smith by James Jauncey, Henry Van Vleck, Dirck Brinkerhoff and Theodore Van Wyck, 1767 March 27 (Box 3, Folder 66)
- Account of Trustees of the Estate of James Duthrie, 1767 March 29 (Box 3, Folder 67)
- Receipt for money paid to city, signed by Dirk Brinkerhoff, Alderman, 1767 October 7 (Box 3, Folder 69)
- Account Receipt for Charles Nichols (Thomas Stewart), 1767 May 19 (Box 3, Folder 70)
- Receipt for Henry Brookman (Charles Nichols), 1767 November 4 (Box 3, Folder 70)
  Receipt for half year shaving
- Receipt for Walter Rutherford (John Turner), 1767 February 2 (Box 3, Folder 70)
  Receipt for yards of fabric, tea, and pair of shoes
- Receipt for Berry Helms (Charles Nichols), 1767 October 13 (Box 3, Folder 70)
  Receipt for wine and cash advanced
- Exchange for 105 pounds to Pay to Mr. Thomas Penington for value received by Mr. Wessel Van Schaick (Messrs. Pike & Green, Merchants in Poole), 1767 June 12 (Box 3, Folder 70)
- Military Bills of Exchange for 10 pounds, 13 shillings, 6 pence to pay Richard Curson, signed George Archibold, Lieutenant - 60th Regiment, 1767 June 25; 1767 August 25 (Box 3, Folder 71)
- Military Bill of Exchange for 15 pounds, 10 shillings, 5 pence to pay Richard Curson, signed Hugh Scott, Lieutenant - 28th Regiment, 1767 July 13 (Box 3, Folder 71)
- Military Bill of Exchange for 50 pounds to pay Richard Curson, signed Thomas Meadow, late ensign - 2nd Batt. 60th Regiment, 1767 October 20 (Box 3, Folder 71)
- Minutes of Council held at Ft. George regarding land on Kattskill granted to A. Prevoost, 1767 January 19 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  Council members were Messrs. Horfmander, Smiths, Watts, Walton, Delancey, Apthorpe, Reade, and Morris.
- Copy of Action of the Council held at Ft. George Dismissing the Charges against Reverend Gerhard Cock, held on October 8, 1767, undated (Box 4, Folder 11)
  Lewy Rawling and Johannes Hardenbergh, influenced by Religious Purity Zeal, exceeded their authority of Justices of the Peaces by compelling Gerhard Cock to appear before them. Gerhard Cock is a Man of Good Character
- Report from his Majesty's Council in New York and Order from His Majesty, 1767 March 24 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  Charters for Religious Institutions -- not Church of England or Dutch
- Return of Small Beer received by 16th British Regiment of Foot in New York, 1767 September 1 – 1768 March 31 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  Each man allowed "half-galloon" a day.
- Receipt of W. Nicolls (Dr. Jacob Van Dyck), 1768 April (Box 3, Folder 33)
  Receipt for bleeding boy, purging powder, nitras powders, et. al
- List of those who were Sons of Liberty and Participated in the Revolt Against Taxation from Lists of names compiled from dinners they attended, 1768-1775 (Box 3, Folder 55)
- Receipt due to Phynds & Ellue (?) (John Empie), 1768 July 119 (Box 3, Folder 64)
  Receipt for fine linen, thread
- Certified Copy of the Account of creditors of John Edward Pryor, an insolvent, 1768 January 11 (Box 3, Folder 65)
- Receipt for John Empie (Henry Remson ___ & Co.), 1768 November 17 (Box 3, Folder 65)
- Receipt for Daniel Mesnard (Charles Nichols), 1768 May 20 (Box 3, Folder 65)
  Receipt for breeches, buttons, thread
- Receipt for 3 bales of copper for John Lamb (John, Thomas, and Samuel Franklin), 1768 August 10 (Box 3, Folder 65)